# 大家好
Hi everyone!
# 剛好今天天氣比較好哦 我去看一下那個鴨子
The weather today is much better. Let's have a look at the ducks.
# 在上面一點
They're up there.
# 看它們過的好不好
Let's see if they're happy with their new life here.
# 你看
Look!
# 那個鴨子
That duck,
# 上次我抓鵝的時候 它老是笑我
it kept laughing at me when I was catching the goose last time.
# 你看
Look!
# 現在還在笑
It's still laughing now.
# 抓隻過來
Let me catch one.
# 還笑
Are you still laughing?
# 等下讓你笑不出來
I'm gonna put an end to your laughter very soon.
# 這鴨子
This duck,
# 上次我買回來都胖的
It was fatter when I bought it,
# 很胖的哦
very fat, you know.
# 現在都瘦了一點
And it gets a bit skinny now.
# 鴨子
Ducky!
# 小鴨子 上次我抓鵝的時候
Ducky, you didn't stop laughing,
# 你一直在笑是不是
when I was catching the goose last time, did you?
# 你笑鴨還是笑我
Were you laughing at the goose or at me?
# 今天就輪到你啦
It's your turn today.
# 走 帶你去
Go! Come with me!
# 帶你去河邊
Come with me to the riverside!
# 明天就把你宰啦
You'll be my dish tomorrow.
# 不叫的
It's not yelping.
# 騙了那麼久都不肯叫的
I've spent so much time deceiving it, but it doesn't yelp.
# 是不是聲音叫的不夠大
Is it because my yelp is not loud enough?
# 這鴨子
This duck,
# 宰好啦
has now been processed.
# 好像有點毛 可能有點毛有點多
There seems to be some feather. Perhaps a bit, it has a bit more feather.
# 沒事
No worries.
# 等下烤一下烤一下這個毛就把它烤掉啦
When we grill it, grill it, the feather will be burnt away.
# 不介意
I don't mind.
# 你看這是
Look! It is,
# 幾個月的
a couple of months old.
# 年齡不是很大 這鴨子
It's not very old, this duck.
# 應該很嫩
It should be very tender.
# 帶你去河邊
I'm taking you to the riverside.
# 然後烤了
And then have you grilled.
# 這個要挖個洞
I gotta dig a hole here.
# 差不多了
It should be fine.
# 就是這個模型
That's exactly the model I want.
# 再把這個堆高一點
I'm making it higher.
# 然後才能
Then I can...
# 這種小石扔到下面去
I throw these small rocks to the bottom,
# 填一下這個小洞
to fill this small hole.
# 你看
Look!
# 現在就像樣了
It now looks like what it should be.
# 就直接這樣子搞
Then we can start right away.
# 把火生在這裡
I'll set the fire here.
# 然後
Then,
# 這
this one...
# 你看 還可以這樣子
Look! I can even put it here.
# 絕對OK
Absolutely OK!
# 怎麼還會不雨的
Why is it still raining?
# 再 加一把火
Let me, light it up once more.
# 先把這個鴨子清理一下
I'll remove the guts from the duck first.
# 加點料酒
Put some cooking wine.
# 來 喝點酒
C'mon! Have some wine!
# 沒那麼痛苦
You're gonna feel less pain.
# 料酒先放旁邊
Put the cooking wine aside first.
# 再搞點
Let's also have some,
# 這葱
spring onions.
# 去兄弟家 路過兄弟家的菜地
We went to, we passed by our buddy's veggie farm.
# 拔了兩根葱下來
So we've taken some spring onions there.
# 這個是 這個是油哦
This is, this is oil.
# 搞點油給你
Let me give you some oil.
# 再搞點鹽
And also some, salt
# 夠了
Enough!
# 加點醬油
Put some soy sauce.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 薑呢
Where's the ginger?
# 沒有帶
I didn't bring it?
# 好啦
Fine!
# 辣椒
Chilli
# 辣椒裡面有薑 (註︰其實我聽到他說「辣醬」的)
There's ginger in the chilli sauce.
# 薑都忘記帶了
I've even forgotten to bring ginger.
# 這辣椒裡面有薑哦
The's ginger in this chilli sauce.
# 來 搞點來
Alright! Put some here.
# 太多啦
Too much!
# 要腌一下啊 給它洗一下
It needs to be marinated. Let me give it a bath.
# 舒服吧
Cool, isn't it?
# 給你洗個
I'm giving you a,
# 洗個澡
giving you a bath.
# 就讓它這樣
So I just leave it here,
# 先腌一下
and marinate it for a while first.
# 太熱啦
It's too hot.
# 我去搞根那個 竹竹同
I'm gonna make a, you know, a bamboo bucket.
# 喝一下這個
And have some,
# 肥仔快樂水
Chubby Happy Drink.
# 誒 刀都搞 搞壞啦
Aya! It, it broke my knife.
# 生活需要儀式感 (註︰這句話出處是>，我見一般的引用都是法語原文，而且使用法語也突顯他突然引經據典的語調變化)
Il faut des rites, dit le renard.
# 這就是儀式感
Et nous disons, c'est notre rite.
# 誒呀
Aya!
# 再來一杯
One more!
# 好爽啊
So cool!
# 好啦
Alright!
# 嘿 你看它動不了啦
Hay! Look! It can no longer move now.
# 沒個水車做得好
This waterwheel is really well made.
# 剛才在我們那邊找了一個這個
I've just discovered this funny thing at our site.
# 還沒用過這個呢 這個噴油的
I've never tried it before. It's for spraying oil.
# 哎呀 用了就更靚
Aya! It makes the duck much more beautiful!
# 你看 這是草珠子哦 你看 (註︰不知是甚麼，照字面翻譯)
Look! This is a grass bead, look!
# 它長在這裡 從上游沖下游長到這裡
It's growing here. It was washed here from the upstream and it's rooted here now.
# 壓起來
Stabilize it.
# 壓下這裡會長起來的
It will grow if it's stabilized here.
# 愛護植物 人人有責
Taking care of plants is a responsibility of everyone.
# 要尊重生命
We need to pay respect to lives.
# 搞個雞翅來吃 (註︰與上次指鵝為鴨一樣，這次指鴨為雞同樣不澄清)
Let me get a chicken wing.
# 熟啦熟啦
It's done, it's done.
# 夾著來
I got it.
# 嗯 好香啊
Um! It smells so good!
# 哇 真的很好吃誒
Wa! It's really tasty!
# 不騙你們
No kidding.
# 有竹子的香味
There's the scent of bamboo.
# 這鴨子抱著竹子來烤
The duck was grabbing the bamboo when it was gilled.
# 嗯
Um!
# 味道真的不錯
It tastes really not bad.
# 就這樣站好哇 別動
Stand still here! Freeze!
# 不聽話
Naughty!
# 哇 真的
Wa! It's really...
# 現在放了辣椒
Now I've put some chilli,
# 有那
So there's,
# 辣椒的味道
the taste of chilli.
# 放的剛好夠辣
The spiciness of just right.
# 嗯 真的 這鴨子好吃
Um! Really, the duck is so tasty.
# 可能在我們
Perhaps we've,
# 在那個養殖場養了那麼久
we've been keeping it at our site for such a long time,
# 肉質全部改變啦
that the texture is completely changed.
# 完全
It's nothing,
# 完全不像買的鴨子一樣
nothing like a duck bought outside.
# 給它鬆綁
Let me untie it.
# 啊 你自由啦
Oh! You're free now
# 嗯~
Um~
# 乾啦
It's dried out.
# 拿回去餵小狗
I'll take back for the doggies.
# 好辣 攝影小哥肯定吃不了
It's so spicy! There's no way that Mr. Cameraman can stand it.
# 直接咬算了
So I'll just bite it right away.
# 你看
Look!
# 脆皮鴨
Crispy duck
# 嗯~
Um~
# 好香啊
It smells so good!
# 你看 全熟啦
Look! It's well done now.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 今天的視頻到這裡啦
The video ends here.
# 嗯 好辣
Um! It's really spicy.
# 滅一下火
Let's put out the fire.